<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Work on John L. Godlee</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/work/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Work on John L. Godlee</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>2024-03-07T00:00:00+0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/work/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Methods to establish square vegetation monitoring plots</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/work/2024-03-07-square_plots/</link>
      <pubDate>2024-03-07T00:00:00+0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/work/2024-03-07-square_plots/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Creating perfectly square permanent plots in dense woodland ecosystems can be a challenge. It&amp;rsquo;s very easy to end up with something more like a diamond or a rhombus, unless care is taken to measure the diagonals of the plot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previously I have set up one hectare permanent woodland tree sampling plots by starting at the SW corner of the plot, then running tapes at 90° going N and E for 100 m to form the W and S edges, respectively. Then to ensure that the edges are actually at 90° you run a tape along the hypotenuse of those edges, which should be 141.42 m long. Then you construct the other two edges (N, E), ensuring that they meet at 100 m, and finally check the length of the other hypotenuse is 141.42 m. The principal drawback of this method is that it requires a tape measure that can cover 141.42 m, or else you have to mess about with two tapes or a long piece of string. Covering a straight distance of 141.42 m is difficult because you often can&amp;rsquo;t see the person standing at the opposite corner. Using 100 m tapes, this method requires a minimum of six tapes. Alternatively you can measure smaller hypotenuse angles at intermediate points along the edges, e.g. at 10 and 25 m, but this means you will have to do many more measurements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below I present an alternative method that I think overcomes these problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Start in the centre of the plot. Run a tape measure going SW (225°) to 70.71 m, using a sighting compass to guide. Run another tape going NW (315°), also to 70.71 m. Run a tape measure between the ends of these two tapes, which should equal 100 m. Adjust the NW tape to get 100 m. Run a tape going NE (45°) to 70.71 m. Run a tape from NW to NE, which should equal 100 m. Adjust the NE tape to get 100 m. Run a tape going SE (135°) to 70.71 m. Run a tape from NE to SE, and another from SW to SE. Triangulate all three tapes running to the SE corner to get 100 m along the edges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This process requires only five 100 m tapes and means that you don&amp;rsquo;t have to span 141.42 m to traverse the full diagonal of the plot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It requires 5 metal poles. One for each corner and one for the centre.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The diagram below shows the layout of tape measures to create a plot in this way. The dotted lines show temporary tape measures, while the dashed lines show permanent tape measures, which form the edges of the plot. The tape measure lines are numbered in the order they should be laid out. The letters next to the numbers (a-e) identify the tape measures. See that line 2b and 5b use the same tape measure, for example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img_full/square_plots/square_plots.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img
          alt=&#34;Diagram of tape measure layout for a 100x100 m square plot.&#34;
          title=&#34;Diagram of tape measure layout for a 100x100 m square plot.&#34;src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/square_plots/square_plots.png&#34; 
      /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;If you did want to stick with the method where you start at the SW corner but wanted to avoid the problem of running a tape 141.42 m along the hypotenuse of the entire plot, you could do hypotenuse measurements at intermediate points, e.g. 25 m (35.36 m) and 50 m (70.71 m). This eliminates the need for tapes longer than 100 m, but does require four or more measures of the hypotenuse, one for each pair of edges.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fieldwork in Ongava Game Reserve</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/work/2023-02-15-ongava/</link>
      <pubDate>2023-02-15T00:00:00+0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/work/2023-02-15-ongava/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I spent a month in Namibia on fieldwork. I was working in a place called Ongava Game Reserve on the south side of Etosha National Park. &lt;a href=&#34;https://ongava.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ongava&lt;/a&gt;
 is a privately owned game reserve with a research centre attached, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.orc.eco/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ongava Research Centre&lt;/a&gt;
 (ORC). I was working with a team of students from NUST, the Namibia University of Science and Technology, and our aim for the field campaign was to set up some vegetation monitoring plots within the Reserve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plots we established are very similar to the plots I set up in Bicuar National Park in Angola during my PhD. The plots are 100x100 m squares. Within each plot we measure every woody stem with a diameter &amp;gt;5 cm at breast height (DBH, 1.3 m). For each stem we record the diameter, species, the tree to which the stem belongs, the location of the stem within the plot using tape measures, information on mortality, and damage, following the &lt;a href=&#34;https://seosaw.github.io/manuals.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;SEOSAW tree plot protocol&lt;/a&gt;
. Each of these stems is then tagged by nailing a numbered aluminium into the stem. We deliberately nail the tags 20 cm above the diameter measurement, so in a few years time we can return and measure the same trees at the same place on the stem to see how much they have grown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img_full/ongava/tree_tag.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img
          alt=&#34;Example of a tree tag nailed into a tree stem.&#34;
          title=&#34;Example of a tree tag nailed into a tree stem.&#34;src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/ongava/tree_tag.png&#34; 
      /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;We used a vegetation map developed by Vera De Cauwer at NUST to determine the major vegetation types on the Reserve and to pick potential locations for the plots ahead of time. The majority of the land area of the Reserve is covered by woodland dominated by &lt;em&gt;Colophospermum mopane&lt;/em&gt; and to a lesser extent &lt;em&gt;Terminalia prunioides&lt;/em&gt;. Most of this woodland occurs on rocky rolling hills composed of Elandhoek light-grey dolomite with thin dark clay soil. There are also Mopane-Terminalia woodlands on some different rocky hills composed of Huettenberg formation darker-grey dolostone, which has bands of chert running through it. These woodlands tend to be more diverse and include species not found elsewhere like &lt;em&gt;Kirkia acuminata&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Sterculia africana&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Moringa ovalifolia&lt;/em&gt;. Around the base of the hills this woodland grades into bushland, also with &lt;em&gt;Colophospermum mopane&lt;/em&gt; and some &lt;em&gt;Terminalia prunioides&lt;/em&gt;, but shorter stature (height &amp;lt;4 m) and with fewer proper trees (single trunk with branching canopy on top). On the deeper clay-silt soil on the flat land, underlaid by calcrete, there is a mixture of sparse mopane parkland that is heavily grazed by ungulate herbivores, sparse to dense shrubland dominated by &lt;em&gt;Catophractes alexandri&lt;/em&gt;, and grassland with very sparse &lt;em&gt;Acacia&lt;/em&gt; species.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our aim was to establish 8-10 plots covering the dominant vegetation units in the Reserve. This includes some areas with few or no trees like the Catophractes shrubland and open grasslands. We established two plots in the open mopane parkland areas. Two plots in Catophractes shrubland. Two plots in grassland. and 6 plots in the Mopane-Terminalia woodland. In the woodland we aimed to try and capture some of the variation in species composition and stand structure, with some plots in less diverse areas and some on the more diverse Huettenberg hills. So in total we established 12 plots, though the grassland and Catophractes plots were very easy to set up. The real work on those plots will come later when others use the ground layer and shrub/small stem SEOSAW protocols to assess the non-tree vegetation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img_full/ongava/catophractes.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img
          alt=&#34;Example of a Catophractes shrubland plot.&#34;
          title=&#34;Example of a Catophractes shrubland plot.&#34;src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/ongava/catophractes.png&#34; 
      /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The parkland is quite interesting. On one of our plots, even though there were only 117 trees, there were 342 stems. Most trees had two or more stems. One tree had 13 stems. It&amp;rsquo;s probable that on some of these parkland areas, the land was previously cleared, or at least the big trees were felled, when the Reserve used to be a farm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img_full/ongava/parkland.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img
          alt=&#34;Example of a mopane parkland plot.&#34;
          title=&#34;Example of a mopane parkland plot.&#34;src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/ongava/parkland.png&#34; 
      /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Finding decent plot locations in the Mopane-Terminalia woodland areas on the rocky hills was more challending than I expected. There are not many roads going through these areas of the Reserve, making large tracts of land essentially unreachable if we are carrying all our equipment. On top of that, one of the main routes to access the southern reaches of the Reserve was cut off for about two weeks due to heavy rain that made it too muddy to get a vehicle through.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img_full/ongava/woodland.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img
          alt=&#34;Example of a rocky woodland plot.&#34;
          title=&#34;Example of a rocky woodland plot.&#34;src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/ongava/woodland.png&#34; 
      /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img_full/ongava/woodland2.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img
          alt=&#34;Example of another rocky woodland plot, this one at lower elevation with deeper soil.&#34;
          title=&#34;Example of another rocky woodland plot, this one at lower elevation with deeper soil.&#34;src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/ongava/woodland2.png&#34; 
      /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;We also had trouble marking the plot corners in the rocky areas. Normally we hammer rebar into the ground to mark the plot corners. But on the rocky hills this was almost impossible. Even if we found a gap in the rocks at one corner, it almost certainly wouldn&amp;rsquo;t coincide with gaps at the other three corners. We resorted to maneouvering huge boulders into place for most of these plots and painting them, then triangulating the corner location by measuring from many nearby trees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img_full/ongava/woodland_boulder.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img
          alt=&#34;A large painted boulder used to mark the corner of a rocky woodland plot.&#34;
          title=&#34;A large painted boulder used to mark the corner of a rocky woodland plot.&#34;src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/ongava/woodland_boulder.png&#34; 
      /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;In Ongava, the management are concerned about animals injuring themselves on bits of metal rebar sticking out of the ground. For those areas on the deeper clay soil where we could get a marker in the ground, I designed an alternative to rebar that remains secure and poses no danger to animals. The marker is made from steel plate, welded to a length of square steel tube. The tube is then hammered into the ground and the plate sits flush with the surface. The plate can then be painted to increase visibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img_full/ongava/corner_diag.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img
          alt=&#34;Schematic diagram of the animal-friendly corner marker.&#34;
          title=&#34;Schematic diagram of the animal-friendly corner marker.&#34;src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/ongava/corner_diag.png&#34; 
      /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img_full/ongava/corner.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img
          alt=&#34;Example of the animal-friendly corner marker.&#34;
          title=&#34;Example of the animal-friendly corner marker.&#34;src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/ongava/corner.png&#34; 
      /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img_full/ongava/corner_situ.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img
          alt=&#34;Example of the animal-friendly corner marker in situ.&#34;
          title=&#34;Example of the animal-friendly corner marker in situ.&#34;src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/ongava/corner_situ.png&#34; 
      /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;In 2024 I hope that the we can do the shrub and ground-layer protocols, then in 2025 it will be time for the first recensus of the large trees. After that, we should fall into a routine of surveying these plots every 3-5 years to track the growth and mortality of the trees, and trends of vegetation change.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fieldwork bumbag</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/work/2023-02-12-field_bumbag/</link>
      <pubDate>2023-02-12T00:00:00+0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/work/2023-02-12-field_bumbag/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been on fieldwork in Namibia, near Etosha, setting up some vegetation monitoring plots in Ongava Game Reserve. This involves measuring the stem diameter of every tree within a 100x100 m square, and affixing a numbered metal tag that identifies that stem so its growth can be monitored over time. This means a lot of time spent walking around in the plot with tape measures, a notebook, a GPS, a compass and many other small pieces of equipment. In the past, I always shoved things in my pockets and carried other things in my rucksack. This meant however, that if I needed something from the rucksack I would have to stop and take it off, rummage around, then close the bag and put it back on. Also, having all these things in my pockets meant that inevitably something would fall out or I&amp;rsquo;d rip a hole in the pocket and spend the rest of the day constantly retrieving stuff from the bottom of my trouser leg.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time, I decided to buy a bumbag to try and solve these issues. Specifically, I purchased the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.snugpak.com/responsepak&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Snugpak Response Pak&lt;/a&gt;
. This bag has a main pocket, two side pockets, and a front pocket, all of them zipped. The front and main pocket also have divider pockets inside to keep stuff organised. The bag has a waist strap with wide webbing and a big plastic buckle. The bag also has a carry handle attached by buckles which go around the main and front pockets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img_full/field_bumbag/bag.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img
          alt=&#34;The Snugpak Response Pak.&#34;
          title=&#34;The Snugpak Response Pak.&#34;src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/field_bumbag/bag.png&#34; 
      /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;For a normal day tagging trees I have been carrying in the bumbag:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Front pocket:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Waterproof notebook&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2x mechanical pencils, one thick, one thin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Biro pen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ruler&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Permanent marker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spare batteries for GPS and headtorch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Main pocket:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Large fixed blade knife&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Small swiss army knife&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Electrical tape&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Orange flagging tape&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compass&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2x DBH tapes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hand lens&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Headtorch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lens cleaning fluid and wipes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Phone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lighter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Side pocket 1:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GPS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Side pocket 2:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First aid kit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img_full/field_bumbag/bag_contents.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img
          alt=&#34;Contents of the Snugpak Response Pak.&#34;
          title=&#34;Contents of the Snugpak Response Pak.&#34;src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/field_bumbag/bag_contents.png&#34; 
      /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;In the field the bag has worked very well. When working with a clipboard I can wear the bag on my front and rest the clipboard on it. Most of the time though, I wear the bag on my lower back where it is more comfortable. I&amp;rsquo;ve also been using the bag for trips to town, wearing it across my shoulder and chest as a messenger bag with the waist strap loosened all the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My main complaint is that the waist strap is sewn a bit low on the bag, meaning that when the bag is full it pulls forwards. I think it would be better if the strap was sewn a bit higher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img_full/field_bumbag/bag_back.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img
          alt=&#34;The bag on my back during fieldwork in a plot.&#34;
          title=&#34;The bag on my back during fieldwork in a plot.&#34;src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/field_bumbag/bag_back.png&#34; 
      /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;To help carry items for actually tagging trees, I also purchased a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.toolstop.co.uk/stanley-stst1-80114-leather-nail-hammer-pouch-p80204/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Stanley STST1-80114 nail belt&lt;/a&gt;
. This has three pockets, a hammer loop, and two slots for pens. In the large pocket I put the nails. In the front smaller pocket I put the current bundle of tags, and in the rear smaller pocket I put a 20 cm DBH measuring stick and the next bundle of tags. I added a shoulder carrying strap made from rope so the bag can be worn a bit higher, rather than carried on a belt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img_full/field_bumbag/nail_belt.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img
          alt=&#34;The Stanley nail belt.&#34;
          title=&#34;The Stanley nail belt.&#34;src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/field_bumbag/nail_belt.png&#34; 
      /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;


</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Track changes in LaTeX for reviewer comments</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/work/2020-03-05-latex_track/</link>
      <pubDate>2020-03-05T00:00:00+0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/work/2020-03-05-latex_track/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have recently submitted a paper and got reviews back with minor changes before publication, YAY! The journal thankfully supplied a LaTeX template for writing the paper which made me very happy, so I wrote the paper in LaTeX and have been using &lt;code&gt;vimdiff&lt;/code&gt; to collaborate with co-authors, for those co-authors who are willing to edit &lt;code&gt;.tex&lt;/code&gt; files, and using &lt;code&gt;.pdf&lt;/code&gt; comments for those co-authors who are less keen on LaTeX.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I have to reply to the reviewers&amp;rsquo; comments and supply a revised version of the manuscript. They recommend on the website using &amp;ldquo;track changes&amp;rdquo; to make the changes clear in the manuscript, however LaTeX doesn&amp;rsquo;t have this functionality, not being a WYSIWYG editor. If I was being smarmy I would recommend they use a plain-text diff utility, but that&amp;rsquo;s probably not a good way to make friends. So I am now looking for a way to do &amp;ldquo;track changes&amp;rdquo; in LaTeX.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have found a few notable options while searching the internet:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ctan.org/pkg/latexdiff&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;latexdiff&lt;/a&gt;
 - A Perl program which automatically diffs and highlights changes between 2 &lt;code&gt;.tex&lt;/code&gt; files, conveniently includes &lt;code&gt;--flatten&lt;/code&gt; if document is divided into separate files using &lt;code&gt;\input&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;\include&lt;/code&gt; statements. See also &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ctan.org/tex-archive/support/texdiff/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;texdiff&lt;/a&gt;
, a less complex option.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ctan.org/tex-archive/macros/latex/contrib/changes&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;changes&lt;/a&gt;
 - A TeX package which allows manual markup with changes as comments in the gutter. Conveniently supplies the &lt;code&gt;final&lt;/code&gt; option to the package declaration, which clears markup.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ctan.org/tex-archive/macros/latex/contrib/changebar/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;changebar&lt;/a&gt;
 - Adds simple highlighted bars where text has been changed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/pedromateo/revdiff-LaTeX&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;revdiff&lt;/a&gt;
 - A LaTeX package which is built specifically with the goal of making the work of reviewers of papers easier by marking changes in the text, adding tags and comments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manually declare highlight options with &lt;code&gt;\newcommand&lt;/code&gt;, e.g. &lt;code&gt;\newcommand{\added}[1]{\color{added}{}#1}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;latexdiff&#34;&gt;LaTeXDiff&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This tool is handy because it automates most of the diff-ing between two .tex files, providing simple red strikethrough lines when text is removed and blue if text is added. I found that this small utility doesn&amp;rsquo;t handle complex changes well though, and is best suited to smaller edits like spelling and word choice. When whole paragraphs start moving around, a manual commenting system is still required, understandably.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had some small issues getting this to run on the Windows machine I am using while working away from home, but I found &lt;a href=&#34;https://tex.stackexchange.com/questions/165543/using-latexdiff-in-miktex&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this Stack Overflow page very helpful in providing a solution&lt;/a&gt;
. I imagine when I try it on a UNIX machine the process will be considerably more streamlined as perl is already installed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;changes&#34;&gt;Changes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A manual change highlighter, which is well developed. I ran into a few conflicts with definition of the &lt;code&gt;\highlight&lt;/code&gt; command, which I think came from the &lt;code&gt;listings&lt;/code&gt; package, but this was solved by redefining my &lt;code&gt;lstlisting&lt;/code&gt; style.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This package adds:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;\added&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;\deleted&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;\replaced&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;\highlight&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;\comment&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It also provides the &lt;code&gt;\listofchanges&lt;/code&gt; command which is similar to the list of figures output.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It provides options to clear the markup using the &lt;code&gt;final&lt;/code&gt; option in the package declaration. There are a bunch of other package options which change what markup is shown in the output &lt;code&gt;.pdf&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;revdiff&#34;&gt;RevDiff&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;revdiff&lt;/code&gt; is another manual change highlighter. I guess the value of manual change highlighters is when a single author is preparing a document to send back to reviewers, so they can see how you have implemented changes. It comes with a few basic functions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;\rnew&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;\rold&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;\rchange&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;\rcomment&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;\rtcomment&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;\renclose&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;\rtenclose&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It provides an option to remove markup and display the new version with &lt;code&gt;\usepackage[clean]{revdiff}&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The package requires you to download &lt;code&gt;revdiff.sty&lt;/code&gt; and keep it somewhere it can be foundby each project, like &lt;code&gt;~/.texmf/&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s unfortunate that comments appear inline rather than in the gutter like &amp;ldquo;track changes&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;manual&#34;&gt;Manual:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If your needs are simple, it&amp;rsquo;s not difficult to create a couple of custom commands which style the enclosed text to show if something has been deleted or added. I&amp;rsquo;ve done this for a long time to add TODO notes for myself, using:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;background-color:#f8f8f8;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-tex&#34; data-lang=&#34;tex&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#204a87;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;\newcommand&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#204a87&#34;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#204a87;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;\todo&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#204a87&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;[1]&lt;span style=&#34;color:#204a87&#34;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#204a87;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;\textcolor&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#204a87&#34;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;red&lt;span style=&#34;color:#204a87&#34;&gt;}{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#204a87;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;\textbf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#204a87&#34;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;#1&lt;span style=&#34;color:#204a87&#34;&gt;}}}&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h1 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only option I found which didn&amp;rsquo;t give me any issues, and the one I ended up using for this project, was &lt;code&gt;revdiff&lt;/code&gt;, which contains the minimum of commands I need and produces smart looking &lt;code&gt;.pdf&lt;/code&gt; markup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For future projects I think I will try and make sure that I will try to incorporate &lt;code&gt;latexdiff&lt;/code&gt; into my workflow from the start. If I change my editing technique then &lt;code&gt;latexdiff&lt;/code&gt; will be able to handle all of this automatically. Possibly if I have one round of &lt;code&gt;latexdiff&lt;/code&gt; and then also use &lt;code&gt;revdiff&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;changes&lt;/code&gt; to provide comments.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Waiting for permits</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/work/2020-04-20-waiting/</link>
      <pubDate>2020-03-04T00:00:00+0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/work/2020-04-20-waiting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While I was on fieldwork I got stuck waiting for an uncreasonable amount of time for research permits so I could carry out my fieldwork. These permits really should have been sorted before I even arrived in Tanzania, and I was assured at the time that they would, but that&amp;rsquo;s another story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Waiting in a dusty office somewhere for days on end without the resources which normally allows one to work efficiently can be incredibly draining. My mind regularly went through a rollercoaster of emotions, being angry, desparate, despairing, sad, hopeful. Then all of a sudden, when the permit does come through, everything changes very fast and you have to be ready to go, so it&amp;rsquo;s difficult to become engrossed in any singular task as at any minute the task might need to be abandoned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I was stuck I did a number of things to stave off being depressed and to pass the time. I read books, this is one of those opportunities where even the most heavy going literature can seem enthralling because there is no alternative media to consume. Last year on fieldwork in a similar situation I read all of Sherlock Holmes and Mary Shelley&amp;rsquo;s Frankenstein. I have also read Joseph Conrad&amp;rsquo;s Heart of Darkness and Moby Dick on previous fieldwork. This time I chose to plough through Bram Stoker&amp;rsquo;s Dracula, which was very enjoyable. At the same time I read Bitter Lemons by Lawrence Durrell, which is a pleasant romantic (in the Victorian sense not the 21st century sense) autobiography of living as a British Ex-pat in Cyprus during the Enosis uprising. Along similar lines I also took the chance to watch lots of Youtube videos, which I could download to my phone, mostly on the subject of making good pizza.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also wrote plenty of blog posts, some about fieldwork and others on more niche subjects that had been on my mind for a while, such as picking a new notetaking app for my Android phone with a detailed comparison of all 69 note editors available on F-Droid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had some real work to do, going through reviewer comments on a paper I had written, but those periods were not nearly enough to fill the interminable wait.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting into a strict routine helped me to track the passage of time and helped it to melt away, as I always knew what was coming next. I would get up at 06:45, have breakfast and wash then leave for the office at 07:30, arrive at 08:00. Sit in the back office catching up on reading and checking any emails that had come in since I last checked until about 10:30, then take a walk to the front office and see what was going on. Lunch at 13:00 for one hour then back to the office for writing and odd jobs until 17:00, then home, shower and relax until 18:30, then go for supper until 20:00 and then bed until the next morning.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
