<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Drinks on John L. Godlee</title>
    <link>http://johngodlee.xyz/recipes/drinks/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Drinks on John L. Godlee</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language><atom:link href="http://johngodlee.xyz/recipes/drinks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Beach Leaf Gin</title>
      <link>http://johngodlee.xyz/recipes/drinks/beech_leaf_gin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://johngodlee.xyz/recipes/drinks/beech_leaf_gin/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 bottle of gin (700ml) 225g white sugar 200ml brandy 400ml young beech leaves  Method  Only use very young beech leaves, freshly stripped from the stem. Add these to a bottle or glass jar (with a secure lid) until the vessel is half full. Add the bottle of gin then stopper the jar and store for 3 weeks Strain the gin off and save. Add the sugar and 300ml water to a pan and bring to a boil.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blackberry Wine</title>
      <link>http://johngodlee.xyz/recipes/drinks/blackberry_wine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://johngodlee.xyz/recipes/drinks/blackberry_wine/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  Blackberries 1.75kg Brewing Sugar 1.5kg Red Wine Yeast (as directed) Yeast Nutrient 1tsp Pectolase 1tsp Campden Tablets (1 per final vessel)  Equipment  Greater than 5 litre fermenting bin w/ lid Funnel Greater than 5 litre glass demijohn Bung with hole Bubbler Airlock Cheesecloth Syphon Hydrometer Steriliser  Method  Wash fruit well Place in fermenting bin Pour over 2 pints (1136ml) of boiling water Stir well, crushing fruit gently When cool add 1tsp of pectolase Cover and leave at room temp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blackcurrant Cordial</title>
      <link>http://johngodlee.xyz/recipes/drinks/blackcurrant_cordial/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://johngodlee.xyz/recipes/drinks/blackcurrant_cordial/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  225 g blackcurrants 150 g sugar zest and juice of 1 lemon 150 ml water  Method  Add sugar and water to large saucepan and bring to simmer Stir in lemon zest and juice Add blackcurrants Cook at low heat until blackcurrants soften and burst Strain through muslin through funnel or jug and into sterilised bottles Scoop leftover into sterilised jar and use as jam Keep for up to 1 month  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Buckwheat Saison with Cashmere Hops</title>
      <link>http://johngodlee.xyz/recipes/drinks/buckwheat_saison/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://johngodlee.xyz/recipes/drinks/buckwheat_saison/</guid>
      <description>Info   Batch size: 40 l
  SRM: 2.8
  IBU: 31.2
  OG: 1.047
  FG: 1.010
  ABV: 5.0%
  Final pH: 4.42
  Boil time: 60 min
  Mash time: 45 min @ 65C
  Hop time: 30 min steep
  Fermentation temp.: 23C
  Ingredients  8.1 kg Briess Pilsen Malt 1.1 kg Arrowhead Mills Buckwheat Flour 225 g Cashmere Hops (8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elderberry Cordial</title>
      <link>http://johngodlee.xyz/recipes/drinks/elderberry_cordial/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://johngodlee.xyz/recipes/drinks/elderberry_cordial/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  Elderberries Demerera sugar Cinnamon stick Lemon  Method  In a saucepan, cover the elderberries with water and bring to a simmer Simmer for 20 minutes Strain the elderberries, save the juice For every 240 ml of juice add: 200g of demerera sugar, 1 cinnamon stick, juice from 1/4 of a lemon Bring mixture to a boil Boil for 15 minutes, stirring regularly, ensure all sugar is dissolved Remove cinnamon sticks Let cool Wash and oven dry some bottles Put liquid in bottles  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elderflower Champagne</title>
      <link>http://johngodlee.xyz/recipes/drinks/elderflower_champagne/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://johngodlee.xyz/recipes/drinks/elderflower_champagne/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  800g sugar Florets from 8 elderflower sprays zest and juice of 4 lemons 0.5 tsp yeast nutrient 5g sachet Champagne yeast / 7g sachet bread yeast  Method  Dissolve sugar in 2 litres of hot water Add to fermenting bin with 3 litres cold water Leave to cool Add lemon zest, juice, elderflower florets, yeast nutrient, yeast Mix well Ferment for 6 days Strain through muslin into fresh bin Leave to settle for about 1 hour Bottle Leave for a week before drinking  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plum Wine</title>
      <link>http://johngodlee.xyz/recipes/drinks/plum_wine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://johngodlee.xyz/recipes/drinks/plum_wine/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  3 kg ripe plums 1 tsp citric acid 1 tsp pectinase 6 pints water 1x 7g sachet bread yeast 1 tsp yeast nutrient  Method  Wash plums in cold water Halve and destone plums Place plums in fermenting bin Add water Add pectinase, citric acid Mash plums with potato masher Cover and leave for 24 hours at ~16-20C Add yeast and yeast nutrient, stir Cover and leave for 5 days at 18-20C Press and strain the pulp using cheese cloth into a second pan Clean cheese cloth and strain again into demijohns Leave for 14 days before drinking Strain again if still very hazy  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
