<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Miscellaneous on John L. Godlee</title>
    <link>http://johngodlee.xyz/recipes/misc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Miscellaneous on John L. Godlee</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language><atom:link href="http://johngodlee.xyz/recipes/misc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chickpea and carrot crepes</title>
      <link>http://johngodlee.xyz/recipes/misc/chickpea_carrot_crepes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://johngodlee.xyz/recipes/misc/chickpea_carrot_crepes/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  250 g chickpea flour 250 g grated carrots 350 ml oat milk 1 tsp caraway seeds (alternatively fennel, mustard, cumin, coriander seeds) Salt Black pepper 1 tsp olive oil  Method  Combine all ingredients except caraway seeds into a blender and blend until a thin smooth batter. Dry roast caraway seeds in a frying pan until fragrant then fold into the batter. Heat olive oil in drying pan, add a ladle of pancake batter to the pan and spread quickly to cover pan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chilaquiles</title>
      <link>http://johngodlee.xyz/recipes/misc/chilaquiles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://johngodlee.xyz/recipes/misc/chilaquiles/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 avocado, sliced 6 eggs 0.5 cup crumbled feta 1.5 cup tortilla chips 2.5 cups tomato salsa 1 lime 3 sprigs cilantro 1 tablespoon olive oil  Method  heat oil in pan Add salsa to pan and simmer for 10 minutes Add chips, and stir into salsa Add feta Crack eggs around edge of pan Cover pan and let sit for 10 minutes or until eggs have set Serve with a spatula, with lime juice, extra feta, avocado, coriander  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chocolate protein bar</title>
      <link>http://johngodlee.xyz/recipes/misc/chocolate_protein_bar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://johngodlee.xyz/recipes/misc/chocolate_protein_bar/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  350 g protein powder (chocolate flavor) 285 g oatflour 5 ml almond milk 100 g 70% chocolate 2 tsp of prepared espresso A little vanilla extract  Optional extras  Almonds Oats Berries  Method  Mix protein powder, oatflour. Mix in almond milk chocolate, espresso, vanilla extract. Put in container and press it out to the edges. Crumble chocolate to very small pieces, melt it using whatever method.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coleslaw</title>
      <link>http://johngodlee.xyz/recipes/misc/coleslaw/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://johngodlee.xyz/recipes/misc/coleslaw/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  0.5 cabbage, shredded 2 carrots, grated 4 spring onions, chopped 2 tbsp sultanas 3 tbsp mayonnaise 1 tbsp wholegrain mustard  Method  Put carrots, spring onions, sultanas in a large bowl and stir to combine In a small bowl, mix mayonnaise, mustard Combine everything together and toss to mix  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Falafel</title>
      <link>http://johngodlee.xyz/recipes/misc/falafel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://johngodlee.xyz/recipes/misc/falafel/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  250 g dried chickpeas 2 tsp coriander seeds 3 tsp ground cumin 1 tsp cumin seeds 2 garlic cloves Small bunch of parsley Small bunch of coriander 1 tsp baking powder Sunflower oil for frying 1 tsp salt  Method  Soak chickpeas in water for at least 12 hours Drain the chickpeas Pulse chickpeas in a food processor Toast the coriander seeds, ground cumin and cumin seeds in a small dry pan Finely chop garlic cloves Combine the spices, garlic, salt and chickpeas then blitz in food processor until they form cohesive balls Chill the mixture in the fridge for at least 30 minutes Form the mixture into ping-pong sized balls Heat oil in a shallow pan until nearly smoking and fry the falafels in batches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freezer vegan breakfast burritos</title>
      <link>http://johngodlee.xyz/recipes/misc/freezer_vegan_breakfast_burritos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://johngodlee.xyz/recipes/misc/freezer_vegan_breakfast_burritos/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  Tortillas Green lentils, boiled and fry fried Refried beans Mushrooms Bell peppers Vegan cheese, shredded Spinach/lettuce Eggs Coriander Salt Paprika Paper towels  Method  In large pan, fry off peppers, mushrooms Add green lentils Whisk eggs and add to pan, combine Combine with rest of ingredients on tortilla Roll up and wrap in paper towel and freeze for up to a month  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hairy bittercress pesto</title>
      <link>http://johngodlee.xyz/recipes/misc/bittercress_pesto/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://johngodlee.xyz/recipes/misc/bittercress_pesto/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  7-10 rosettes hairy bittercress 1 clove garlic 0.5 chilli 25 g grated cheese 10 walnut halves 10 g pine nuts 2 tbsp olive oil 0.5 lemon 0.5 tsp sugar  Method  Rinse the cress and roughly chop into a mixing bowl Heat garlic cloves for a few minutes on low heat to mellow the flavour Chop the garlic and chilli into the bowl Add all the other ingredients Blend with a stick blender  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lip Balm</title>
      <link>http://johngodlee.xyz/recipes/misc/lip_balm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://johngodlee.xyz/recipes/misc/lip_balm/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  Shea butter 12.5g Beeswax 7.5g Cocoa butter 5g Almond and Calendula oil 15ml  Method  Melt shea butter, beeswax, cocoa butter in metal bowl over boiling pan When melted, add almond and calendula oil Mix well Pour into tins while hot  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tomato Ketchup </title>
      <link>http://johngodlee.xyz/recipes/misc/tomato_ketchup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://johngodlee.xyz/recipes/misc/tomato_ketchup/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  5 lbs fresh tomatoes, chopped small 0.25 tsp cayenne pepper 0.25 cup apple cider vinegar 1 tsp salt 2 tbsp molasses 2 tbsp honey 0.25 tsp ground clove 0.25 tsp ground cinnamon 1 tbsp brown or Dijon mustard 0.5 tsp Worcestershire sauce 0.25 tsp ground pepper 0.25 large onion, diced 0.5 clove garlic, minced  Method  Place tomatoes in large deep pan Gently mash tomatoes and cook for 30 minutes on low heat Puree tomatoes with stick blender Pour tomato puree into slow cooker Add remaining ingredients and cook on low overnight Puree mixture again Remove lid of slow cooker and cook on medium for ~ 3-4 hours Puree mixture again Funnel into sterilised jars  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wood Sealant</title>
      <link>http://johngodlee.xyz/recipes/misc/wood_sealant/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://johngodlee.xyz/recipes/misc/wood_sealant/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 part beeswax 3 parts mineral oil  Method  Suspend bowl over simmering water Add beeswax and mineral oil Heat and stir until clear pour into jar and let cool  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
