<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bread on John L. Godlee</title>
    <link>http://johngodlee.xyz/recipes/bread/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bread on John L. Godlee</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language><atom:link href="http://johngodlee.xyz/recipes/bread/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Basic loaf</title>
      <link>http://johngodlee.xyz/recipes/bread/loaf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://johngodlee.xyz/recipes/bread/loaf/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  400 g brown flour 100 g white bread flour 7 g sachet of yeast 1 tsp salt 1.5 tsp olive oil 300 ml warm water  Method  Mix together flour, yeast, salt Rub in olive oil, removing lumps Pour in the water in stages and mix to a dough. Depending on the flour used more or less water ay be required. Knead for about 10 minutes Cover with some oil and return to bowl Cover with plastic and leave to rise for 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cheesy beer bread rolls</title>
      <link>http://johngodlee.xyz/recipes/bread/beer_rolls/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://johngodlee.xyz/recipes/bread/beer_rolls/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  815 g strong white flour 1 tbsp dried yeast 2 tsp salt 4 tbsp (55 g) butter 60 ml honey 480 ml pale ale beer 200 g sharp grated cheddar  Method  Combine the flour, yeast, salt, 2 tbsp butter Rub in the butter Add the honey and beer mix until thoroughly combined Add 120 g cheese, mix until combined Lightly grease a bowl and let dough rise for ~1 hour Lightly grease a baking pan Divide the dough into 12 pieces and form into balls Place balls side by side in pan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ciabatta (Yukon Magazine, Alpine Bakery)</title>
      <link>http://johngodlee.xyz/recipes/bread/ciabatta/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://johngodlee.xyz/recipes/bread/ciabatta/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Poolish  500 ml warm water 750 ml white flour 2 tsp dry yeast 0.5 tsp salt  Dough  750 ml white flour 20 ml warm water 2 tsp salt 3 tbsp milk 3 tbsp olive oil 2 tbsp rosemary soaked in 2 tbsp olive oil 0.5 cups chopped Kalamata olives  Method Poolish  Dissolve yeast in water in large mixing bowl Leave for 5-10 minutes Add flour and salt Mix until smooth batter formed Cover and leave in warm place for 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coriander stuffed paratha</title>
      <link>http://johngodlee.xyz/recipes/bread/coriander_paratha/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://johngodlee.xyz/recipes/bread/coriander_paratha/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  150 g plain flour 60 ml water 2 tbsp oil 0.75 tsp salt Large bunch fresh coriander 1 red chilli 2 tsp cumin 0.25 cup feta or paneer 1 clove garlic  Method  Mix the flour, oil and salt together in a bowl. Mix in more or less water bit by bit with a wooden spoon or paddle until the dough forms a cohesive, supple, non-sticky ball. Knead on a lightly floured work surface until the dough isn&amp;rsquo;t shaggy and sticky.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drop biscuits</title>
      <link>http://johngodlee.xyz/recipes/bread/drop_biscuits/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://johngodlee.xyz/recipes/bread/drop_biscuits/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  255 g all-purpose flour 1 tbsp baking powder 1 tsp salt 1 tsp granulated sugar 141 g cold unsalted butter, cut into cubes 0.75 cups whole milk, plus 1 to 2 tablespoons if needed  Method  Preheat oven to 200C Whisk together flour, baking powder, salt and sugar Cut the butter into the flour until it is a coarse meal with some small pea-size pieces Using a fork, stir in the milk until evenly moistened Scoop the dough into 8-10 rough mounds and place on a greased baking sheet Bake the biscuits until just golden brown, about 15-20 minutes Serve warm or cooled  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Everyday flatbreads</title>
      <link>http://johngodlee.xyz/recipes/bread/everyday_flatbreads/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://johngodlee.xyz/recipes/bread/everyday_flatbreads/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  150 g plain flour 60 ml water 2 tbsp oil 0.75 tsp salt  Method  Mix the flour, oil and salt together in a bowl. Mix in more or less water bit by bit with a wooden spoon or paddle until the dough forms a cohesive, supple, non-sticky ball. Knead on a lightly floured work surface until the dough isn&amp;rsquo;t shaggy and sticky.. Divide the dough into four and shape into balls.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frank Pinello pizza dough</title>
      <link>http://johngodlee.xyz/recipes/bread/pinello_dough/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://johngodlee.xyz/recipes/bread/pinello_dough/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  340 g water 6 g yeast 28 g extra virgin olive oil 480 g all-purpose flour 12 g salt  Method  Bloom the yeast in a little lukewarm water until pastey Combine the water, bloomed yeast, oil and hald the flour in a bowl Mix until a thick batter Add remaining flour and salt Knead until elastic Cover and rise for at least 2 hours or overnight in the fridge Form into pizza directly from fridge  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>J. Kenji Lopez-Alt pizza dough</title>
      <link>http://johngodlee.xyz/recipes/bread/lopez_alt_pizza_dough/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://johngodlee.xyz/recipes/bread/lopez_alt_pizza_dough/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  500 g white bread flour 5 g yeast 12 g salt 330 g water 10 g extra virgin olive oil  Method  Mix all ingredients together until hydrated Fold mixture every thirty minutes for first 3 hours Cover with cling film and leave overnight in fridge Divide the dough into two, shape into balls. Proof at room temperature for 4 hours  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Khachapuri - Georgian Cheese Bread </title>
      <link>http://johngodlee.xyz/recipes/bread/khachapuri/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://johngodlee.xyz/recipes/bread/khachapuri/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 tsp salt 1 tbsp granulated sugar 1 tsp dried yeast 3.5 cups white flour 1 cup water 0.5 cups milk 1 tbsp olive oil  Filling  1.5 cups cottage cheese, thoroughly drained 1.5 cups shredded mozarella 1.5 cups feta cheese 5 eggs  Method  Combine the salt, yeast, sugar and flour Heat water and milk until about 50C Pour water and milk into dry ingredients and knead until smooth and elastic Add oil to the dough and knead for another minute Drizzle olive oil into a deep bowl and place the dough in the bowl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meloui flatbreads </title>
      <link>http://johngodlee.xyz/recipes/bread/meloui_bread/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://johngodlee.xyz/recipes/bread/meloui_bread/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  400 ml warm water 4.5 tsp dried yeast 1 tbsp sugar 750 g plain flour or wholewheat flour, or a combination of the two 50 g powdered milk or 250 ml plain yoghurt 1 tbsp salt 125 ml extra virgin olive oil  Method  Combine 120 ml of water, yeast and sugar,until it begins to foam Sift together the flour, powdered milk (if using), salt. Add yoghurt (if using), yeast mixture, remaining water, olive oil Mix until fully incorporated Knead in the bowl until soft and sticky Add drop of olive oil, and mix over surface of dough Cover with towel and leave to rise for 1 hour Put a bit of oil on a surface Knock dough back then pull off small pieces, about the size of a small orange With each piece, roll to a smooth ball then flatten so about a palm width across and rest on oily surface for about 20 minutes Preheat oven to 230 C Grease 2 baking sheets with oil Add flour to work surface, roll out each dough piece into thin rounds Bake for 5-7 minutes Serve warm  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Naan </title>
      <link>http://johngodlee.xyz/recipes/bread/naan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://johngodlee.xyz/recipes/bread/naan/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  0.25 cup warm water 1 tbsp sugar 3 tsp yeast 0.75 cup plain yoghurt 0.75 cup warm milk 4 cups flour 1 tsp salt  Method  Combine the yeast, sugar and water in a bowl. Let it foam for 10 minutes Add the flour and salt, mix then knead for 5 minutes Let rise for around an hour or until doubled in size Split into 12 Stretch or roll Fry in a dry pan on high heat until browned then flip Optionally brush with melted butter mixed with finely chopped coriander  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Olive Rosemary Foccacia</title>
      <link>http://johngodlee.xyz/recipes/bread/olive_rosemary_foccacia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://johngodlee.xyz/recipes/bread/olive_rosemary_foccacia/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  500 g bread flour 15 g salt 4 g yeast 325 ml water 0.25 cups olive oil 4 oz pitted olives, sliced 0.25 cups roasted pistachios, roughly chopped or lightly pounded in pestle and mortar 2 tbsp fresh rosemary leaves, roughly chopped Coarse salt for dressing  Method  Combine flour, salt, yeast, water in v. large mixing bowl Mix with wooden spoon Cover with cling film or put in plastic bag Rest on counter top for 8-24 hours Transfer dough to lightly floured surface then form into a ball Pour half the oil into a baking tray Transfer dough to tray, coat in oil Cover with cling film and let stand for 2 hours Preheat oven to 200C Spread olives and pistachios over dough surface and press down with fingertips Drizzle with remaining oil, sprinkle with rosemary and salt Bake for 16-24 minutes or until done  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pizza Margherita</title>
      <link>http://johngodlee.xyz/recipes/bread/pizza_margherita/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://johngodlee.xyz/recipes/bread/pizza_margherita/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  300 g Strong bread flour + extra for kneading 1.5 tsp yeast 1 tsp salt 1 tbsp olive oil + extra for drizzling 100 ml tomato passata Handful of fresh basil / 1 tsp dried 1 garlic clove, crushed 125g ball mozzarella, sliced handful shaved parmesan handful cherry tomatoes, halved 200 ml water  Method  Combine flour, yeast, salt in large mixing bowl Pour in water and olive oil Mix until soft wet dough Knead on floured surface for 5 minutes until smooth Cover with towel and set aside for enough time to double in size, or put in fridge overnight for a slow rise mix passata, basil, garlic, season to taste with salt and pepper Preheat oven to 220C Roll out the dough with a rolling pin Add toppings, drizzle with olive oil, Bake for 8-10 minutes  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Potato bread</title>
      <link>http://johngodlee.xyz/recipes/bread/potato_bread/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://johngodlee.xyz/recipes/bread/potato_bread/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  385 g mashed potato 375 g bread flour 1.5 tsp salt 1 sachet of yeast 1/3 cup oat milk (or normal milk) 3 tbsp olive oil  Method  Mix the flour, salt and yeast. Add the milk, mashed potato and olive oil. Stir to combine until a dough forms. Knead for 5 minutes or until elastic. Cover with a damp towel for 45 minutes. Line a baking sheet with baking paper.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
